制作: 星际迷航中国字幕组 (https://www.startrekchina.org)
翻译: 诺北 & 中二的老马 & rubin & σ-algebra & 小羊 & Zelpens
校对: Imprinting & narwhrl
时轴: narwhrl
特效: narwhrl
日期: 2025-08-05
《星际迷航：新世界》前情提要
Previously on Star Trek: Strange New Worlds...
佩利亚中校
Commander Pelia,
这是斯考特上尉 他需要你的帮助
this is Lieutenant Scott. He needs your help.
我认识斯考特
I know Scotty.
教授
Professor.
在人类文化中
Is it not tradition
隆重的浪漫表达 难道不是传统吗
to make a grand romantic gesture,
还是我又对人类的关系产生误解了
or have I again mistaken how human relationships work?
你和克莉丝汀不是决定
I thought you and Christine
暂时分开 给彼此一点个人空间吗
had decided to give each other some space.
确实
Indeed.
史波克
Spock.
克莉丝汀
Christine.
这是科尔比博士
This is... Dr. Korby.
我的约会对象
My date.
舰长
Captain,
我们又探测到了那个太空辐射
we're picking up that space radiation again.
无论如何
Whatever this is
它都不像是布鲁塔星云的本土产物
does not appear to be native to the Blootar Nebula.
这是在太空 上尉
This is space, Lieutenant.
没有什么所谓的 本土
There's no such thing as... native.
我们都是宇宙的孩子
We're all children... of the cosmos.
舰长 在过去一小时内
Cap, in the past hour,
我们又有十四名船员
we have had 14 more crew members report
因忧郁症去医务室报道
to medbay on account of melancholia.
我这辈子只见过一次这种场面
I have seen this only once before...
在战场上
in the war.
那我们需要点帮助了
Then we'll need a leg up.
但是舰长 我们不在管制星域内啊
But Captain, we're outside of regulation space.
跟我谈管辖权你还太嫩了 上尉
Don't lecture me on jurisdiction, Lieutenant!
太空管辖权的书 可是我编的
I wrote the book on space... jurisdiction.
而我最出名的可就是
And I am known for my...
语言措辞
diction.
好了
Now...
给我联系 艾戈尼亚人
...get me... the Agonyans.
艾戈尼亚人是极其危险的太空生物
The Agonyans are extremely dangerous space creatures.
你以为我不知道吗
You don't think I know that?!
联系他们 上尉
Make the call, Lieutenant,
为了布鲁塔星云和太空
for the sake of the Blootar Nebula and space.
舰长 太空电话接通艾戈尼亚人了
Captain, I have the Agonyans on the space-phone.
放到屏幕上
On viewer-screen.
联盟星舰冒险号向您问好
Greetings from the USS Adventure.
我 便是这艘船的舰长
I am... the captain of this vessel,
代表整个外太空行星联盟
representing the whole of the Alliance of Outer Space Planets.
我是兹普诺普 来自艾戈尼亚三元帝国
I am Zipnop of the Triathic Agonyan Empire.
崇拜我们吧 渺小可悲的人类粮堆
All worship to us, small, pathetic, human food-piles.
我们在布鲁塔星云里检测到了
We scanned an unusual level of radiation
水平异常的辐射
in the Blootar Nebula.
尽管这是在贵国的管辖区外
Even though this is outside of your empire's... jurisdiction.
好一个弥天大谎
That is a lie!
可悲却美味的人类们四散的谣言
Spread by pathetic but delicious humans.
但是 医生
And yet... Doctor,
我们的船上不是出现了大量的
have we not received multiple cases of melancholia
忧郁症病例吗
aboard this ship?
没错 舰长
We have, Cap.
忧郁症不是只有在人类接触到
And doesn't melancholia only occur
艾戈尼亚辐射时 才会发病吗
when humans are exposed to Agonyan radiation waves?
的确如此
True.
将 死
Check and... mate.
啊 你发现了我们的计划
Argh! You have figured out our plan.
就算我们需要你们的脑细胞来给辐射供能
We may need your brain cells to power our radiation,
但你们绝对阻止不了我们
but you will never stop us!
没门 因为我们必须阻止你们
We can, and we will because we must.
这是我们星际探险家的职责
It is our duty... as space explorers.
没机会了 我们要先灭了你
Not if we destroy you first.
我倒要看你怎么灭
I'd like to see you try.
但是舰长 要是被他们得逞了怎么办
But Captain, what if they can?
你们人类有很多脑细胞
You humans are rich with brain cells.
只要你们给我们脑细胞
If you give them to us,
我们就可以不毁灭你们
we will choose not to destroy you.
给你们一分钟的时间
You have one minute to
来满足我们的要求
comply with our wishes.
艾戈尼亚人把我们逼上了绝路
The Agonyans have put us in an impossible situation.
只剩一条出路了
There is... only one solution.
绝不能给出我们的脑细胞
We can't give them our brain cells.
从科学角度讲 我们需要脑细胞
We need it... for many science reasons.
舰长 艾戈尼亚人
Captain, the Agonyans
正在向我们发射核能激光
are firing a series of nuclear lasers at us.
升起护盾 准备迎接冲击
Shields up! Brace for impact!
用光子射线还击
Fire photonos beams at them!
他们走了
They're gone.
随之而去的还有
And so is...
-我们的脑细胞 -不
- our brain cells. - No!
我们怎么办
What do we do?
首先 我们找到艾戈尼亚人
First... we find the Agonyans...
拿回我们的脑细胞
...retrieve our... brain cells,
然后
and then...
找回我们的快乐
we get back our joy.
银河系 人类最后的边疆
Galaxies: the last frontier.
这是联盟星舰冒险号的故事
This is the tale of the USS Adventure
她长达八十四个月的任务
on its 84-month mission
去迷航至宇宙最遥远的角落
as it treks across the furthest reaches of the universe,
去努力寻找未知生命
striving to find unknown life,
未解之谜 与未至之地
unexplained phenomena, and new space destinations.
勇往直前 超越极限
To go forward, to go beyond,
更勇敢地踏足更加遥远的未竟之地
to go further and bolder than anyone ever before.
安全官日志
Security Officer's Log.
进取号即将穿过基托利安带
Enterprise is about to pass through the Kitolian Belt,
其环绕着的中心是一颗中子星
which centers on a neutron star.
不过在进取号研究中子星的时候
But while Enterprise studies the neutron star,
我被安排了另一项同等重要的工作
I've been assigned a separate but equally important task.
算它作双重任务吧
Call it a dual mission.
您是想让我去玩游戏吗 长官
You want me to... play a game, sir?
星际舰队觉得他们找到了
Starfleet believes that they have figured out
能够进行长期超光速旅行的方法
a solution to long-term, faster-than-light travel.
不用多久 星舰就可以持续巡航五年以上
Starships will soon be able to go for more
而不用中途返回联邦
than five years without returning to Federation.
为了散心和释放压力
So, games and entertainment as
我们需要游戏和娱乐
distraction and stress release.
这个我们要测试的设备是叫做
Now the device we're going to be testing is called
「娱乐室」
the "Re-creation Room"?
简称 全息甲板
Holodeck, for short.
-这个好听 -没错
- Sounds better. - Yeah.
这东西是基于战斗模拟器改进的吗
Is this based on battle simulators?
毕竟 模拟器每一关我全都打过了
'Cause I-I've beaten every one of those.
不然为什么我们选你呢
Why do you think we picked you?
但是这种模拟器通常都设在星站上
But those simulators are usually on starbases.
它会占用大量的能量和算力
They take up huge amounts of energy and processing power.
我们的船真的撑得起来吗
Can our ship actually handle it?
我们就是来搞明白这一点的
That's what we're here to figure out.
我们的命令很明确
Our orders are clear.
在进取号研究坍缩中子星的同时
While Enterprise studies the collapsing neutron star,
你要来测试全息甲板
you're going to test the holodeck.
实战测试一下它能不能在出任务时启用
Put it through its paces under a real mission.
证明它能在真实的 严苛的环境下运作
Show it could work under genuine, rigorous circumstances.
您觉得一场游戏对全息甲板来说能有多严苛 长官
How rigorous do you expect a game on the holodeck to be, sir?
嘛 这是个测试 上尉
Well, it's a test, Lieutenant.
我以前当试飞员的时候
The kind of thing I'd do all the time
对测试只有一种态度
when I was a test pilot.
意思就是
Which means,
往死里测试它
you push it as hard as you can.
你跟我说过你想要点挑战
You told me you needed a challenge.
不用谢
You're welcome.
我打扰你了吗
Am I interrupting?
我选择用舞蹈训练代替
In lieu of my normal morning calisthenics,
我每天早上的体操运动
I have elected to continue dance training.
已经差不多要结束了
I have nearly completed my routine.
噢 我来了你也不用停啊
Oh, don't stop on my account.
计算机 播放歌单 史波克十九号
Computer, begin playlist: Spock 19.
探戈
Tango.
很上进啊
Ambitious.
我只是顺道来问一下 斯考提让你修的
I just swung by to ask about the field emitters
全息甲板力场发射器现在怎么样了
for the holodeck that you've been fixing for Scotty?
抬眼 上尉
Eyes up, Lieutenant.
你之前对我说 眼神是探戈生根的地方
You told me the eyes are the anchor of the tango.
不是吗
Are they not?
我的诊断分析差不多都完成了
My diagnostics are nearly complete.
力场发射器都已经重新校准完毕
I have realigned the field emitters.
你和斯考特先生只要设计好程序
The holodeck should be operational as soon as you and
全息甲板即可投入运行
Mr. Scott finish designing a program for you.
谢谢
Thank you.
戴着监控针会让你难受吗
Has the monitoring pin been much of a burden?
我都忘了自己还戴着这东西
I actually forgot I was wearing it.
这是好事
That is a good thing.
能捕捉到你自然的状态是最好的
It is best if it captures you in a natural state,
这样全息甲板就能根据你的参数
so the holodeck can construct the most realistic environment
营造出最逼真的环境
for your specifications.
说到这里 你选好全息模拟的主题了吗
Speaking of, have you chosen a subject for your simulation?
还没呢
Not yet.
我对人类娱乐领域涉猎未深
I am not well-versed in human entertainment,
不过暴力与休闲的主题似乎比较热门
but violence and relaxation seem to be popular.
此外
Along with...
浪漫故事亦是如此
...romantic narratives.
艾米莉亚
Amelia.
《艾米莉亚·穆恩》是什么鬼
Amelia Moon? What the hell is that?
20世纪60年代的地球侦探小说
Detective stories from Earth in the 1960s.
那位把我从戈恩人手里救出来的舰长
The-the captain of the ship that rescued me from the Gorn--
给了我一本
he-he gave me a copy,
看得我爱不释手
and I became obsessed.
艾米莉亚是个局外人 但她总是莫名地
Amelia was an outsider, but she always found herself
被卷入各种谋杀案 绑架案
in the middle of a murder, or a kidnapping,
或者闹了什么乌龙的抢劫案
or a heist gone wrong.
但她总是能伸张正义
And she always got justice,
无论情况如何
no matter what.
这么说吧
Let's just say...
我被她带坏了
she had an effect on me.
数据库里找到了112项结果
There are 112 of them in the database.
这些内容拿来建立模拟绰绰有余了
That's plenty of material to form the simulation.
不过要让模拟就这么一直运行下去
Although, the computer might have trouble
计算机会有点吃力
keeping the simulation running as it is.
考虑到佩利亚离舰休假了
Uh, Pelia's on shore leave,
所以你的意思是 又要请史波克出马了
so, you-you want to call in Spock again?
小事一桩 我搞得定
It's nothing I can't handle.
我能把全舰其他系统
I-I can balance the processing needs
的处理需求给匀过来
from the rest of the ship.
不过 有个小问题
Although, there is one wee wrinkle.
呃 全息投影的角色
Uh, the holographic characters
必须做到纤毫毕现才够格
need to be incredibly detailed to pass muster.
分辨率这么高的生命特征数据
The only bio-signatures we have at that resolution
我们只在传送器模式缓冲区里有
are from the transporter pattern buffer.
我们会利用他们的形象
We'll use their likenesses
来创造全息可交互角色
to create holographic interactive avatars.
就等你准备好了 上尉
Ready when you are, Lieutenant.
计算机 以艾米莉亚·穆恩系列小说为参考
Computer: using the Amelia Moon novels as reference
并根据我自身的侦探水平
and factoring in my skills as an investigator,
创造一个我难以解决的悬疑故事
create a new mystery that I will find challenging to solve.
史波克 我
Spock, I...
我以为你已经完成诊断分析了
I thought you'd finished running diagnostics.
我想确保计算机系统能在
I wanted to ensure the computer system is functioning
正常参数内运行
at normal parameters.
多谢你的关心
I appreciate your concern.
但是 不要告诉斯考提
But, uh, don't tell Scotty.
他为了这事忙得累死累活的
He's been working very hard on this.
确实 他很敏感
Indeed. He is sensitive.
你随时都可启动并评估该程序
You may run and evaluate the program on your command.
计算机
Computer:
运行程序
...run program.
我能真的闻到大海和香烟的味道
I can practically smell the ocean and the cigarettes.
在全息甲板的有限空间内吸烟并非明智之举
It would be unwise to smoke in the confines of the holodeck.
或者说 吸烟本就不明智
Or at all.
不 我只是觉得这 这真是太
No. I just meant it's-it's very, um...
栩栩如生
Lifelike.
确实如此
Indeed.
我读了那么久的艾米莉亚啊 我只是
I have spent so many hours reading about Amelia. I just...
我不敢相信我真的能亲身扮演她
I just can't believe I actually get to be her.
好吧 正如我的祖先
Well, as my ancestor,
阿瑟·柯南·道尔爵士会写的那样
Sir Arthur Conan Doyle would write,
「游戏开始了」
"The game is afoot."
谢谢 史波克先生
Thank you, Mr. Spock,
但这是个单人档
but this is a single-player situation.
随时为你效劳
I am available,
需要我的帮助就随时叫我
should you decide you need my assistance.
祝你好运 上尉
Good luck, Lieutenant.
艾米莉亚·穆恩
Amelia Moon!
-谢天谢地你来了 -乌乎拉
- Thank goodness you're here. - Uhura.
乔尼·格洛斯 我们在去年十一月
Joni Gloss. We met briefly
你解决那起福克斯惨案的时候有过一面之缘
when you handled that Fox fiasco last November.
你保住了我的客户的事业
Saved my client's career,
才让他没被关进圣昆汀监狱
and kept him out of San Quentin.
好了 跟我来
Now, follow me.
是我发现了尸体
I'm the one who found the body.
不是我还能是谁
Of course, I did.
我总是第一个到
I'm always the first to arrive.
在这座城里我有条规矩
And I have a rule in this town.
如果你准时 那你就迟到了
If you're on time, you're late.
如果你迟到了 你就死定了
And if you're late, you're dead.
现在好了 真的死人了
In this case, literally.
当然 这可不是我干的
Not by my hand, of course.
你会记下这句话的吧
You'll put that in your record?
不过 你不是第一个到的客人 对吧
Only, you weren't the first guest to arrive, were you?
他们当中有一个人杀了托尼
One of them killed Tony,
我只是不知道是谁
I just don't know who.
所以我就联系你了
That's why I called you.
我需要你在条子赶来之前
I need you to solve this
解决这个案子
before the cops show up.
不然他们就会把我们所有人都抓起来
They will arrest every one of us
只是为了把故事卖给那些八卦小报
just to sell the story to the gossip rags,
接着转眼间 你还没反应过来呢
and then, poof, before you know it,
我一半的客户都被炒鱿鱼了
half my clients, out of a job.
所以我要保护好你的客户
So, protect your clients.
当然啦 除了凶手
Except the murderer, obviously.
我要跟那家伙解约
I'm going to drop them.
尸体在哪里
Where's the body?
在这里
In there.
说实话
Staying honest,
我几乎不敢看他
I could barely look at him.
我会在客厅里拖住其他人
I'll stall the others in the sitting room
你尽管去做你该做的事
while you go do what it is you... do.
有火吗
Got a light?
真棒
Fantastic.
加州 好莱坞
Hollywood, California.
豪宅 影星
Mansions, movie stars,
和命案
and murder.
窒息性死亡
Strangulation.
但凶器是什么
But with what?
在今晚九点钟
At 9:00 p.m. tonight,
托尼·哈特
Tony Hart,
洛蒙德电影制片厂负责人
head of Lomond Picture Studios
在家中被人勒死
was strangled in his own home.
然而凶器未知
But with what?
凶手未知
And by whom?
千万别忘了还要查清动机
And don't forget about the "why."
找到杀人动机
Find your motive,
你就能找到凶手
and you've got your killer.
一般来说 动机都悄悄地
Usually, a motive hides
藏在阴影之下
quiet secrets hidden in shadows
藏在紧闭的门后
and behind closed doors,
但我能看出这案子的要素十分齐全
but I could see this case had it all.
激情 绝望
Passion, desperation,
嫉妒 暴怒
jealousy, rage.
至于这些嫌疑犯嘛
And as for the suspects,
有些人你估计看着还眼熟
you may recognize some of the guests
洛蒙德电视台的太空冒险时间档
from Lomond's television space adventure hour,
《星际边疆》的组员
The Last Frontier,
例如该节目的主创 TK·贝洛斯
including the show's creator TK Bellows
以及曾是演员 后来成为制片人的 桑尼·卢皮诺
and former actress turned producer Sunny Lupino.
该剧的大明星 阿德莱德·肖
The show's stars-- Adelaide Shaw,
麦克斯韦·圣和李·伍兹也在这里
Maxwell Saint and Lee Woods-- are also here,
还有肖的心头肉 安东尼·麦克比奥
along with Shaw's main squeeze, Anthony MacBeau.
而你已经见过顶级经纪人乔尼·格洛斯了
And you already met power agent Joni Gloss.
这场聚会的东家 托尼·哈特死了
Your host, Tony Hart, is dead,
而凶手就是你们之中的某人
and one of you murdered him.
先别急 等一下
Hold your horses.
我们这里为什么会有人想谋杀哈特
Why would one of us want to murder Hart?
因为你的节目就要被砍了
Because your show was about to be canceled.
开玩笑 我们可是大热门啊
Canceled? But we're a hit.
哦 收视率
Oh. Ratings.
好了 接下来
Now, here's how this is going to go.
任何人都不许从那扇门出去
No one is gonna walk out of that door
也不能打电话
or make any phone calls.
你也不行 威廉·莫里斯
Even you, William Morris.
我们得好好待在一起
We're all gonna get real cozy
直到把这一切都弄清楚
until we've worked this all out.
这种事不该发生在我头上啊
This can't be happening. To me.
目前已知的信息有
What we know:
今晚九点 有人用不明武器
At 9:00 p.m. tonight, someone strangled Tony Hart
在卧室中勒死了托尼·哈特
with an unknown weapon in his bedroom.
我们知道凶手就在这个房间里
We know the killer is in this room,
而且我们知道 动机很可能是因为
and we know the likely motive is the cancelation
《星际边疆》要被砍了
of The Last Frontier.
而解开这个谜题的关键
And the key to this puzzle...
像玻璃般清晰明了
...is as clear as glass.
什么
What?
等等 不是 不是我干的
Wait, it wasn't... it wasn't me.
大家都知道你喝的是什么 朋友
Everyone knows your drink, pal.
我相信你
I believe you.
此外 你更喜欢偏冷色调的粉色
Besides, you favor a frostier shade of pink.
但这款色可是经典的
But this shade is classic.
蜜丝佛陀的红宝石红
Max Factor's Ruby Red,
1955年发售 并在各大
released in 1955, and splashed
时尚杂志上大肆宣传
all over fashion magazines
就涂在这位模特兼流行歌星标志性的嘴唇上
on the iconic face of model and pop star
正是桑尼·卢皮诺
Sunny Lupino.
不然呢 我可是引领潮流的巨星
What can I say, I'm a trendsetter.
但这证明不了我就是凶手
But that doesn't make me a killer.
确实不行
That doesn't.
但这个可以
But this does.
《星际边疆》是你身为制片人出品的第一个项目
The Last Frontier was your first project as a producer.
你拼命争取让它成功播出
You fought to get it on the air,
从你跟工作室的关系 到你的前夫
leveraged your relationships with the studio
全都是大好的资源
and your ex-husband.
你把你的整个职业生涯都押上去了
Bet your whole career on it.
托尼和我是离婚了
Tony and I were divorced,
但我们在工作方面一直都是互利互助
but we were still very much invested in each other's success.
你的投入比绝大多数人都多 不是吗
You were a little more invested than most, weren't you?
想把太空剧带进美国家庭的客厅可是很烧钱的 所以
It's expensive to bring space into American living rooms, so
你私下借了笔贷款
you took a personal loan from...
借黑帮的钱 但要是剧被砍了的话
...the mob. But if the show was canceled,
你就没法偿还这笔债务了 于是
you'd never be able to pay it back, so...
你杀了托尼以求这部剧能继续播出
...you killed Tony to keep it on the air.
关于此人我只知道一件事 他是我的粉丝
The only thing I know about that man is that he's a fan.
来找我要签名的
He wanted an autograph.
那又何必用长焦镜头呢
Why the telelens, then?
我当时在佩里诺饭店跟约翰尼享用晚餐
I was having dinner at Perino's with Johnny.
那人姓卡森 想让我参与一个全国广播公司的项目
Carson. He was trying to talk me into a project at NBC.
托尼一直都在监视我
Tony was keeping tabs on me
想确保我没有跟别人勾搭上
to make sure I wasn't being unfaithful.
以防我想背后坑制片厂
To the studio.
但你说对了
But you're right.
我确实有做自己的投资
I did invest my own money,
但钱不是从黑帮借来的
I just didn't take it from the mob.
我把房子卖了
I sold the house.
我和托尼的第一个房子
Mine and Tony's first house.
啊 你不是可喜欢那间房子了吗
Oh, but you love that house.
在说服艾尔弗雷德让我出演《乌鸦》之前
Until I convinced Alfred to put me in Crows,
我还只是个无名小卒
I was just another pair of lips.
但奥斯卡奖一到手 机会来了
But that Oscar opened doors.
机会到手之后我干什么了 去买豪车吗
And what did I use it for, my own star vehicles?
我没有 我听到TK在推销
No. When I heard TK's pitch
他的《星际边疆》
for The Last Frontier,
那一刻我就意识到 这部剧可不一般
I knew it was special.
只要能拯救它 你做什么都愿意
And you'd do anything to save it.
那不是废话
You're damn right, I would.
我甚至找托尼商量我的计划
I even came to Tony with a plan.
-但他拒绝了 -他同意了
- But he refused. - He agreed.
我们还在商讨细节呢
We were going over the details
结果聊了一半被麦克斯韦·圣打断了
when Maxwell Saint interrupted us.
假如你真想知道
If you really want to know
托尼到底怎么了
what happened to Tony,
问他去
talk to him.
天哪
Oh, my God.
李 她死了吗
Lee? Is she dead?
你知道我是个演员 不是医生吧
You know I'm an actor, not a doctor, right?
但是你看她这模样
But, yeah. I mean, look at her.
怎么看都是死了
She's obviously dead.
死于中毒
Poison.
斯考提 你在忙吗
Scotty, you busy?
有点忙
A bit busy, yeah.
你的模拟程序能耗有点超标 咋了
Your simulation is pulling a wee bit more power than expected. Why?
以战斗模拟器为原型开发的全息甲板
Base a holodeck on a battle simulator
反应也会和战斗模拟器一样
and it's going to act like one.
什么意思
What does that mean?
它看穿我了 预判了我的行动
Well, it's figured me out, learned my moves.
好像真的是我的敌人一样
Just like an enemy opponent.
这种设置怎么改
Well, how can I change that?
不用改 我需要换个视角
No, I need a fresh eye,
找一个和我思维不同的人来
someone who won't see things like I do.
在第57本书《纸月旅馆谋杀案》里面
In book number 57, Murder at the Paper Moon Inn,
艾米莉亚·穆恩找了一个搭档
Amelia Moon needed a partner.
这个嘛 恐怕我帮不了你
Well, I'm afraid it can't be me
没了我进取号要停摆的
if you want the Enterprise to continue running.
噢 没事
Oh, no, that's okay.
我觉得我已经有个完美的舞伴了
I think I might have the perfect dance partner already.
史波克  多谢你来帮我
Spock, thank you for coming.
我会尽力给你提供全面的帮助
I'm here to assist in any way I can.
不过 我有一事想问
Though, may I ask,
既然你已经输给了全息甲板的程序
if the holodeck has defeated you,
为何不直接结束任务呢
why not just end the mission?
听着 派克舰长给了我很明确的命令
Look, Pike gave me very clear orders:
要用严苛的条件来测试这个设备
Test the device under rigorous circumstances.
以及 我还没输呢 是我升级了
Also, it didn't defeat me, I leveled up
然后它提高了难度
and then it increased the difficulty.
再说了
Besides,
艾米莉亚·穆恩在抓到凶手前绝不放弃
Amelia Moon doesn't give up until she gets her man,
我也一样
and neither do I.
我已经大致了解了案件
I have briefed myself on the case.
侦探穆恩的搭档是什么样的
What was Detective Moon's partner like?
想来应当是个好手
Proficient, I assume?
他是个笨手笨脚的傻子
He was a bumbling idiot.
-听起来没什么用处 -确实
- That does not seem useful. - No.
但你的用处可大多了
You will be much more so.
这是谁啊
Who's this guy?
史波克侦探
Detective Spock.
我的同事
He works with me.
他怎么穿得跟来参加睡衣派对一样
I didn't know this was a pajama party.
等等
Hang on.
是演员分配部派你来的吗
Did Central Casting send you?
就他那耳朵 开玩笑的吧
What, with those ears?
史波克侦探不看电视
Detective Spock doesn't watch television.
合着这哥们是共产党吗
So he's a communist?
更像那种爱看电影的文艺逼
More likely one of those cinema snobs.
这有什么关系
What does it matter?
全息柯克似乎情绪很激动
The holo-Kirk seems particularly agitated.
正常 他可是我的头号嫌犯
He should, he's number one on my suspect list.
辛苦你赶过来了
Thanks for coming so fast.
看看这些波动
These fluctuations... here.
它们变得越发频繁了
They're becoming more frequent.
考虑到那颗坍塌中的中子星只有六小时航程远
We are six hours from a collapsing star.
有一些小波动是正常的
Minor surges are to be expected.
大家全在通宵工作
Everyone's pulling an all-nighter.
我甚至跟派克建议让奥特加斯复职
I even recommended Pike reinstate Ortegas.
你信任她吗
And you trust her?
当然
I do.
辅助能源貌似也出现了些问题
Auxiliary power also seems to be having issues.
这应该不在标准情况之下了
This seems beyond standard.
别担心 一切都在掌控之中
Don't worry, I've got everything under control.
传感器严重过载 电容电力故障 全息二极管分析中
哇 这传感器过载得太夸张了吧
Wow, that is a sensory overload.
噢都是正常的 都在掌控之中
Oh, all normal, all under control.
全向全息二极管产生的变量
The omnidirectional holo-diodes produce
实在是太多了 不太好全都关照到
a tremendous number of variables to keep an eye on.
需要找个人帮你吗
Do you need a second set of eyes?
没事 我能搞定
No, I've got it.
以我的经验看 有时候多一个人
In my experience, sometimes a second set of eyes
可能会适得其反 我能搞定的
can be... detrimental. I-I can handle it.
好的 但我需要先签收你的工程日志
Okay, but I do need to sign off on your engineering logs
然后再回去处理中子星的事
before returning to work on the neutron star.
祝你能够打破之前那位总管留下的
Fingers crossed you improve upon the haphazard example
一团乱麻的先例
set by your... supervisor.
是的 我知道佩利亚的日志实在是
Yes, I'm familiar with, uh,
臭名昭著
Pelia's infamous logs.
老鹰都能把眼睛看瞎
An eagle could go blind from reading them.
-这就撑不住了吗 -没有没有
- Broken already? - Oh, no, no.
小毛病 在测试阶段很正常
Just a wee bug, to be expected with
不用大惊小怪
beta phase testing.
这模拟器毕竟这么大 它会自动调取
You know, a simulator this big will automatically pull
算力来进行补偿 你明白的
processing power to compensate, but, you know,
这算不上啥问题
it's not a problem.
只要转移一些能量 没事啦
I'll just, um, divert a little juice. Yeah.
虽说拉安是在实地亲力亲为的那个
La'An may be running this test,
不过
but, uh,
坚强的后盾可是你啊
you're the failsafe.
明白明白
Understood. Loud and clear.
我一定能搞定哒
But, you know, I've got it.
圣先生 是你杀了托尼·哈特和桑尼·卢皮诺吗
Mr. Saint, did you kill Tony Hart and Sunny Lupino?
不是
Nope.
是你吗
Did you?
桑尼说 托尼死之前
Sonny said you and Tony
你和他在吵架
were fighting before he died.
小打小闹罢了
A tiff. A row.
退一万步说 吵了两句吧
A tangle, maybe.
没啥好搬出来讲的
It's not even worth discussing.
不过是因为有人嫉妒了
It was jealousy.
嫉妒
Jealousy?
你的手镯
Your cuff.
在作案现场有一个一模一样的
There was an identical one at the crime scene.
这是哈特的秘书送我的廉价小玩意
A little trinket from Hart's secretary.
她喜欢我
She likes me.
你们在搞外遇
You were having an affair.
被你发现了
You caught me.
哈特先生对此有意见 是吧
And Mr. Hart had an issue with this?
刚巧只是因为他在和同一位秘书搞外遇啦
Well, only because he was having an affair with the same secretary.
听起来很复杂
sounds complicated.
并没有 随便玩玩罢了
No, not really. It was casual.
人与人之间一旦开始紧密合作
You work closely with people,
奇妙的事情自然会发生
and things happen.
想必二位一定深有感触
You two must know how that goes.
什么 我们
What? We--
没有 这是你的事
No, this-this is about you,
与别人无关
not... anyone else.
听着 我是一个演员
Look, I'm an actor.
我喜欢演戏
I like drama,
但绝对没必要出于这种理由杀人
but it's certainly nothing to kill for.
另外 我早骗过了哈特
And besides, I had already convinced Hart that
跟他说我与那位秘书分手了
it was over between me and the secretary.
他怎么就信你了
And how did you do that?
我和麦克斯韦鬼混吗
Me and Maxwell?
绝对百分百没门
Absolutely 100% never.
你好像情绪很激动啊
You seem awfully heated about that.
他是个极端大男子主义的自大狂
He's a chauvinistic egomaniac.
光是跟他待在同一个布景里我都忍不了
I can barely stand to be on set with the guy.
我跟他上床图啥啊
Why would I go to bed with him?
你知不知道这部剧要被砍了
Were you aware that the show was being cancelled?
知道些小道消息
I heard whispers.
你对此有什么想法
How did you feel about it?
这个嘛
Well,
我的台词和裙子
my lines and my skirts have been
越往后拍越短
getting shorter and shorter with every episode,
唯一一个
and the only person
为我的角色争取权利的就是桑尼
who ever fought for my character was Sunny.
现在她也死了
And now she's dead, so...
你知道我在西区出演海达·高布乐时
Did you know that I was just 18 when I played
才十八岁吗
Hedda Gabler on the West End?
二位侦探 我是个好演员
I'm good at what I do, Detectives.
但别人似乎只关心你的感情生活如何
But all anyone seems to care about is your love life.
肯定很令人沮丧吧
Must be frustrating.
是啊 很沮丧
Yeah, it is.
我只是想要在职业生涯中
But is it wrong to want love
兼顾爱情和我应得的尊重 这有什么错吗
and to be taken seriously in my career?
那你觉得 为什么你和圣先生
So, why do you think there are persistent rumors
之间的流言总是屡次三番地被提起呢
about your affair with Mr. Saint?
你觉得卢皮诺小姐是个什么样的人
How did you feel about Miss Lupino?
你是说 我有没有杀她的动机
You mean, did I have a reason to kill her?
没有
No.
我敬佩她
I admired her.
她不愿意只做一个花瓶
She couldn't settle for being a work of art.
她想要成为艺术的创作人
She wanted to make art.
你对艺术很看重啊
Art means a lot to you.
艺术就是一切
It's everything.
如果说我想要赠给世人什么礼物
If I can give a gift to the world,
那就是帮助人们解放
I want to help people unleash
心中那头艺术的野兽
the artistic beast inside of them.
怎么解放你这所谓的艺术野兽
How does one "unleash the artistic beast"?
我一直在办一个艺术家沙龙
I've been doing an artists salon.
李之前可能和你们讲过了
Lee probably told you about it.
具体陈述一下沙龙的活动
What goes on at an artists salon?
麦克弹吉他
Mac plays guitar.
其他人有的唱歌 有的画画
Others sing, paint.
你呢
And you?
李写些东西
Lee writes.
确切地说 她最近在写一部剧本
She's been writing a screenplay, actually.
电影的剧本
A movie.
什么剧本
A screenplay?
怎么问起这个
Why?
麦克跟你们说的吗
Mac told you that?
在达科他州上演的一部西部片
A western set in the Dakotas.
被害人房间里就有一本剧本
There was a script in the victim's room,
写的是达科他州的故事
about the Dakotas.
还有谁知道剧本的事
Who else knew about this?
打算畏罪潜逃哈
Guilty conscience got you running?
不是畏罪 是胃病
More like a weak stomach.
多年心血付之东流
Must be hard to watch something you've poured so much into
很难受吧
just disappear.
心里确实是疙疙瘩瘩的
It's not my favorite feeling, no.
是不是收视率太低了 不能续订第二季
But the ratings were too low to warrant a season two?
粉丝虽然不多 但还是充满热情的嘛
Our fanbase is small, but it's quite passionate.
伍兹小姐的西部电影
Were you threatened
有没有让你感到受威胁
by the Western motion picture Miss Woods wrote?
李又写了一部西部片吗 挺好的
Lee wrote another Western? Good for her.
她就喜欢吊死在这种早过时了的题材上
She'll never tire of that dying genre.
所以 你知道剧本的事
So, you knew about the script?
不觉得嫉妒吗
You weren't jealous?
谈谈电视剧被砍的事吧
What about the cancellation?
这也是你之前就知道的吗
Did you know about that, too?
于是你就撕合同了 冲冠一怒 是吗
Is that why you ripped up your contract? Out of anger?
你知道他们是怎么评价第一季的吗
Do you know what they say about a show after its first season?
不知道 说说看吧
No. What do they say?
有一种没过脑子的美感
Practically writes itself.
哈特撕的合同 不是我
Hart ripped up that contract, not me.
真是帮了我个忙
He was actually doing me a favor.
你早就想离开节目了吗
You wanted to leave the show?
有本我中意已久的书 版权在华纳兄弟公司手里
Warners has the rights to a book I've been chasing.
他们甚至同意让我来执导了
They're even gonna let me direct.
是啊 我真心喜欢这部剧
Yeah, I-I-I love our show,
但那可是电影啊
but movies...
电影才能真正改造人的灵魂 孩子们
That's how you change hearts and minds, kids.
这么说来 剧被砍了你还挺开心的
So, you're happy the show was being canceled?
侦探大人
Oh, Detective.
我是作家
I'm a writer.
我对什么事都高兴不起来
I'm never happy about anything.
但我没杀人
But I didn't kill anyone.
他们身为同事
They all worked together,
却任由私人情绪泛滥
yet allowed their emotions to jeopardize
妨碍了共同的工作
the very work that they all shared.
这是什么
What is that?
李·伍兹的剧本
Lee Woods's script.
我就知道有什么不对劲
I knew something was off about it.
看 没封面
Look, no title page.
为什么呢
But why?
也许是为了隐去剧本的作者
Perhaps to hide the connection to the writer.
不 不是贝洛斯干的 他不在乎这个
No, no, no, not from Bellows. He didn't even care.
不对
No.
有没有可能 不是李撕掉的
What if Lee's not the one who removed it?
拉安
La'An...
看起来吊灯是
The chandelier appears to have been
被故意切断来伤害我们的
purposefully cut to harm us.
为了阻止我们
To stop us
因为我们已经靠近真相了
because we're close.
剧本没有封面
The screenplay doesn't have a title page
是因为剧本被人偷走了
because it was stolen.
哈特偷了李的剧本 把作者改成其他人
Hart stole Lee's script and was going to credit someone else,
也许是想归功给某个男的 那个年代常有这种事
probably a man, because that happened all the time back then.
于是她就把哈特杀了
So she killed him for it.
有更要紧的事
There is a more pressing matter.
怎么有血
Blood?
我记得全息甲板不是有有安全协议的吗
Well, I-I thought the holodeck had safety protocols.
也许是出故障了
Perhaps they are malfunctioning.
我们得离开这里 不要冒险
We should get out of here, not risk anything else.
计算机 终止程序
Computer, end program.
斯考特先生 把程序停下
Mr. Scott, please end program.
计算机 显示拱门
Computer, arch.
这下
So...
我们关不掉它了
we can't shut it off,
而且程序真的能伤害我们
the program could actually hurt us,
我们还出不去
and we can't get out.
正是如此
Indeed.
斯考特中尉 你在找我吗
Lieutenant Scott, are you looking for me?
这样 假设一下我们出了点通讯故障
Say I've got this hypothetical communications problem,
你能不能给我点指导 像往常一样
could you advise me on this problem that, again,
我是说假设哈 并不是真出了乱子
you know, it's not a real problem,
你不要按字面意思理解这个词
in the traditional sense of the word "problem."
我大概明白你的意思
I think I followed that.
假设有一种非常小概率的事件发生了
In the highly unlikely event
就是说呢 我和全息甲板里的拉安彻底失联了
that I were to have lost all contact with La'An inside the holodeck,
你的建议是什么
what would you advise?
如果失联的话
Well, if comms failed,
我会绕过局部子处理器
I'd bypass local subprocessors
直接联通光电数据网络
and patch directly into the optical data network.
好 我们再假设一下
Yeah. Imagine in this hypothetical,
我已经这样尝试了若干次
like, I've already done that, multiple times.
假设说来 我会去直接关闭模拟
Hypothetically, I'd shut the simulation down.
现在看来 我估计你
Which, I'm assuming,
在假设条件下 已经试过了
you've already, hypothetically, done.
斯考提啊 你是说拉安被困在全息甲板里了吗
Scotty, are you telling me La'An is trapped in the holodeck?
你要不试试 敲敲门
Have you tried knocking on the door?
或者把门炸了
Or simply blowing it off?
全息甲板里面的各类力场 牵引光束还有高精度二极管
The holodeck is a complex balance of forcefields, tractor beams,
之间的平衡极为复杂
and precision-guided diodes,
而且设备全都直连主机
all hardwired in.
所以炸门会瘫痪整个计算机系统
So, blowing it up would crash our entire computer system.
修不好的那种 经过我的计算
Permanently. Per my calculations,
除非拉安上尉走完程序的流程
the only way to unlock the program
没有其他办法解除程序锁定
is for the lieutenant to complete it,
但她完全不知情
but she's unaware of this.
怎么样才能走完流程
What does completing it entail?
破一桩一九六九年的好莱坞谋杀案
Solving a murder mystery set in 1969 Hollywood.
我会帮你的
I'm on it.
谢谢你 少尉
Thank you, Ensign.
你知道这都不是假设吧
you-you know that wasn't all hypothetical?
是啊 你刚开口我就知道了
Yeah, I caught on almost immediately.
好的
Okay.
很不幸 在模拟程序里
Unfortunately, I was unable to access the panel
各面板无法响应
while in the simulation.
我还是联络不上斯考特或是舰上的任何人
I still can't reach Scotty over comms or anyone on the ship.
所以我们既有计算机问题
So, we have a computer problem
又有通讯问题
and a communications problem.
别忘了还有谋杀案
We also have a murderer problem.
如果杀手要对我们动手 我们真的会死
If the killer comes after us, we could actually die in here.
所以也许唯一的活路是抓出凶手
So maybe the only way to survive is to catch the murderer.
也就是说
Which means...
得把案子彻底破掉
we're going to go solve this mystery.
我只是
I-I just...
无法相信你想离开剧组
can't believe you wanted off the show.
你不是也想离开吗
You also wanted off the show.
你猜怎么着 我看你就是恨我
You know what I think? I think you hate me,
还恨我给了你这辈子
and you hate the fact that I gave you the best job
能接到的最好的工作
that you're ever gonna have.
你在威胁我吗
Are you threatening me?
都听见了吧
Did you all hear that?
TK在威胁我
TK threatened me!
他讲的是实话
He tells no lies.
你又懂上了
What would you know?
你只是给阿德莱德当跑路的下家的
You're only here as Adelaide's escape hatch.
你这又什么意思呢
What is that supposed to mean?
观众不喜欢你
Audiences don't like you.
至少我懂怎么正常地念台词
At least I can deliver a line realistically.
我那叫表演
It's called acting.
你知道什么才是不正常的吗
And you know what's not realistic?
一个女大副
A lady first officer.
承认现实吧 你早就明白自己没什么前途
Face it. You knew your days were limited.
于是你才嫁了这个摇滚巨星
That's why you agreed to marry Mick Bowie over here,
做他的小迷妹 跟着他演出就不显眼了
so you could disappear on tour as his groupie
就没人会注意到你的职业生涯早完蛋了
and nobody would notice that your career was dead!
你们都给我闭嘴
Everyone shut up, now!
好了
Right.
李·伍兹去哪儿了
Where is Lee Woods?
这个睡衣男到底是哪儿冒出来的
And who is this guy?
她死了
She's dead.
乔尼·格洛斯
Joni Gloss.
不是这样的 你误会了
It's not what it looks like.
我只想是来借个火
I was just looking for a light.
我找到她时她就已经死了
She was dead when I found her.
星际边疆这部剧要是被砍
You had quite a bit of cash to lose
你的经济损失应该会不小吧
from the cancelation of The Last Frontier, didn't you?
我在节目里有三个客户 你算算损失大不大
I had three clients on that show. You do the math.
但我没杀托尼·哈特
But I didn't kill Tony Hart,
虽说我恨不得杀了他
though I wish I had.
为什么
And why is that?
因为砍掉《星际边疆》
Because canceling The Last Frontier
是托尼做过的最蠢的事
is the stupidest thing Tony's ever done.
你知道这样的一部剧有多难得吗
Do you realize how rare a show like this is?
TK想要做的是通过科幻世界
TK wanted to give audiences a digestible reflection
来给观众们呈现他们能看懂的 关于现实世界的反思
of their own world through the lens of fantasy.
通过外星人的橡胶头套与故事情节中的隐喻
Social commentary with rubber masks
给出社会评论 科幻嘛 就是这样的
and buried metaphors. You know, science fiction.
公司反对他的远大图景 是吗
And the studio did not agree with this vision?
他们更倾向于
They were more...
谨言慎行
cautious.
不愿意在社会上掀起波澜 这帮懦夫
Didn't want to "make waves." The cowards.
TK希望星际边疆能取代这个腐烂的世界
TK wanted Frontier to take our rotten world,
远离蝇营狗苟 不仁不义
with its warts and injustices,
给观众一些更美好的东西
and give audiences something better.
这么多高大上的 就凭这每周一集的太空冒险故事?
And all of that with weekly space adventures?
你不觉得这个理念很鼓舞人心吗
You don't find the idea inspiring?
你不觉得看到这部剧的孩子们也许会
You don't think some kid out there is going to see this show
尽其余生仰观宇宙之大 探索星辰大海吗
and spend the rest of their life searching the stars?
你不觉得对一个人来说
You don't think a person can love a piece of art
所深爱的艺术 又或是音乐或故事
or music or a story so much
都能够治愈心灵吗
that it heals them?
通过展现人们从未知晓的一部分自己
Shows them parts of themselves they'd never even seen before?
他们不会觉得看到了希望吗
And give them hope?
呃 是这个道理
Well, no, of-of course I do.
像这样的作品就不该有完结的一天
A show like this could've gone on forever.
它能让一代又一代的粉丝知道
Given generations
在这里 他们能够被看见 感受到归属感
of fans a place to feel seen, to belong,
让他们能敢于重新拾起信仰
something to believe in again,
无论他们是谁 来自什么地方
no matter who they were or where they came from.
但要是没有第二季 这一切都是空谈
But you can't do any of that without a season two.
终于给我找到火了
Finally, a light.
假壁炉
A fake fire?
托尼对电影的品味无可挑剔
Tony had impeccable taste in film,
但他对装饰的品味真是没救了
but his sense of decor is just tragic.
壁炉里是什么
What's inside the fireplace?
赛璐珞胶片
Celluloid film.
在22世纪就停用了
Discontinued in the 22nd century,
许多人说这是电影行业的损失
many say to the detriment of cinema.
我想这就是杀人凶器
I think this is the murder weapon.
但同时也是一份记录的载体
But it's also a recording.
这胶片里录有杀手想销毁的东西
There's something on this film the killer wanted to destroy,
但他和乔尼一样看错了这片壁炉
but made the same mistake Joni did.
史波克 我们必须看看这里面有什么
Spock, we have to see what's on this.
好吧 中子星马上要坍塌了
All right, neutron star collapse is imminent.
乌乎拉 扫描仪在收集数据了吗
Uhura, are scanners receiving data?
正好收到 舰长
Right on time, sir.
舰长 我监测到一片伽玛射线爆发
Captain, I'm detecting a gamma burst
正冲向我们的航行路线
heading into our flight path.
它的能量强度超乎预料地高
It's heavier energy than expected.
传感器已经过载
The sensors are overloading.
升起护盾
Shields up.
打开黄色警报
Let's go to yellow alert.
奥特加斯 带我们下去
Ortegas, take us down.
尽可能绕开它
Steer as clear as you can.
我也想
I'd like to,
但能量刚刚忽然被消耗了一大截
but we just had a massive power drain.
引擎无响应了
Engines aren't responding.
护盾也是
Neither are shields.
舰桥呼叫科学实验室
Bridge to Science Lab.
斯科特先生 我们的系统怎么了
Mr. Scott, what's happening to our system?
好吧 看起来全息甲板的能耗
Well, it seems the holodeck
还是比我预料的要多一点点
is pulling a wee bit more power than I'd anticipated.
那就把它关了
Then shut it down.
舰桥有情况 我现在就需要能量
We have a situation on the bridge, and I need power, now.
好的 但这事很复杂 舰长
Yeah, it's not quite that easy, sir.
红色警报
Red alert.
斯科特先生
Mr. Scott,
没有引擎动力 我们就会迎面撞进
without engine power, we are going to fly head-first into
一片巨大的伽玛射线暴
a massive gamma-ray burst,
这样我们无法幸免
and we are not going to survive it.
斯科特先生 我需要解决方法
Mr. Scott, I need a solution.
呃 我可以手动
Uh... I can manually
一点一点地把能量转给你
reroute power to you in small increments.
这应该有点用
That should give you something.
快 现在就做
Do it. Do it now.
你大概有30秒的时间加速
You've got roughly 30 seconds of acceleration.
你能做到吗
Can you make that work?
我可以一试
I do like a good challenge.
我们躲过了
We're through.
希望不要再来一次爆发了
Let's hope there isn't another one.
斯科特先生 我想跟努尼恩·辛格上尉谈谈
Mr. Scott, I'd like to talk to Lieutenant Noonien-Singh.
呃 我看看能否接通她
Uh, let me see if I can get her.
我们继续假设一下
Let's say I figured out a way to contact La'An.
我找到联络拉安的办法了
Hypothetically.
那你就是我的假设的英雄了
Then you'd be my hypothetical hero.
我觉得你不能用老方法联系她
I think you can't get through in a conventional way
因为人工智能屏蔽了所有
because the AI is blocking out all comms
模拟程序以外的通讯
that don't come from the simulation.
它拒绝让她跟任何不是程序内的人说话
It's refusing to let her talk to anyone who's not part of the program.
它居然在进化
It's-it's... it's evolving.
所以你需要让它相信 你也是全息投影
So you need to convince it you're a hologram, too.
太空管辖权的书
I wrote the book
可是我编的
on space jurisdiction,
而我最出名的可就是
and I am known...
语言措辞
...for my... diction.
好了
Now...
给我联系 艾戈尼亚人
get me... the Agonyans.
艾戈尼亚人?
The Agonyans?
-哦 停 -什么
- Oh... cut! - What?
继续拍 继续拍
Keep rolling. Keep rolling.
-好的 -是不是有点过头了
- Okay. - Was that too much? I-I...
我觉得挺好的
I thought it was great.
-我明白你的意思 -好的 好的
- I completely felt it. - Okay, okay, okay, okay.
好的 在片场安静点
Okay. Quiet on the set.
安静点
Quiet on the set.
又有什么问题
What's the problem now?
哦 我该怎么说呢
Oh, where do I even start? Uh,
要不你试试着像真正的人类一样说台词
maybe you could try delivering the line like an actual
哪怕就一次
human being for once?
哦
Oh.
好吧 要是你写的台词
Well, maybe if you wrote a line...
值得我演个正常人 我倒乐意试试
...worth delivering, I could try to.
这一幕到底讲的是什么
What is this scene even about?
不是关于资本主义的吗
I thought it was about capitalism.
这我真没想到
Big surprise.
你没有理解剧本
You didn't understand the script.
这都第几次了
Again.
这里没有哪怕半个人理解我的远大图景吗
Does no one here care about my vision?
呃 先生
Uh, sir?
干什么
What?!
有你的电话 呃
There's a call. Um...
你这电话不太碰巧
Not a good time.
什么 我
What? I...
你不能这样 我
You can't do that. I-I...
我成就了这部剧 你不
I am the show. You c--
我
I...
你会后悔的
You'll regret this.
拉安 拉安
La'An? La'An?
拉安 我不知道你能不能看见我
La'An, I don't know if you'll see this,
但这是我唯一跟你联系的机会了
but it was my only chance of getting a message to you.
全息甲板把全舰其他区域的算力
The holodeck is pulling all computer
都快吸干了
processing power from the rest of the ship.
我们阻止它的唯一方式就是终止程序
The only way to stop it is to end the program,
也就是说你得解开这个谜题
which means you have to solve the mystery.
等等 如果我们用掉了
Wait. If we're pulling all processing power,
包括护盾 导航和维生系统的所有算力
that includes shields, navigation, life support.
他们会死的 我们都会死
They could die. We could all die.
你说得很准确
An accurate assessment.
我说得很
An accurate asse...
你怎么能一点都不关心
How are you not more concerned?
这关乎我们的朋友 我们的命
These are our friends, our lives.
你要求我保持客观冷静
You asked me to remain detached.
我只是按你的要求行事
I am merely doing as you requested.
我们现在知道贝洛斯确实非常在乎
We now know that Bellows did indeed care very much
剧集被砍的事
about the cancellation.
对 这给了他动机 并且他有机会动手
Yep. That gives him motive, and he had an opportunity.
但他没理由杀伍兹或者卢皮诺
But he had no reason to kill Woods or Lupino.
她可没砍这部剧
She didn't cancel the show.
她愿意付出一切来拯救它
She would have done anything to save it.
确实如此
That's true.
甚至开除我也在所不惜
Including firing me.
真奇怪 如此鼎鼎大名的侦探
You know, for such a smart detective,
也能犯这种蠢
you're awfully stupid.
他们没有取消这部剧
They weren't canceling us.
他们只是把我换掉了
They were replacing me.
这可是我自己的剧啊
On my own show.
或许我们应该坐下 冷静地谈谈
Perhaps we should sit down and calmly discuss this.
我很冷静 我来这就为了要回我的工作
I came here calm. I came here to ask for my job back.
你知道这有多羞辱人吗
Do you have any idea how humiliating that is?
然后他拒绝了你 于是你就
And when he said no, that's when you--
我谁都没杀啊
I didn't kill anybody!
那就把枪放下
Then put the gun down.
你真的会伤到人
You could actually hurt someone in here.
这不再是个游戏了
Th-This isn't a game anymore.
这从来不是个游戏
This was never a game.
这是我的事业
This is my career.
我才不要放下枪
And I'm not putting the gun down
因为我不是杀人凶手
because I'm not the killer.
但这里总有一个人是
But someone else here is.
我吗
Me?
我是被请来这查案的
I was brought here to solve this case.
我知道
I know.
艾米莉亚·穆恩 伟大的侦探
Amelia Moon, the great detective.
她到哪儿 死亡就会跟到哪
Death just seems to follow her wherever she goes.
不 这太离谱了 我
No, this is crazy. I--
还有你这个穿着奇装异服的古怪朋友
And your strange friend in his odd clothes,
看起来完全没有七情六欲
so devoid of emotion.
总是在观察
Always watching,
学习
studying.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait a minute.
你是电视台派来的吗
Did the network send you?
你就是替代我的人吗
Are you my replacement?
不 你这个蠢货
No! You idiot!
他只是来帮我的
He was just here to help me!
我不是 我没有
I-I didn't. I didn't.
史波克 史波克
Spock? Spock?
我没事
I'm okay.
谢天谢地
Oh, thank God.
怎么了
What is it?
是你
It's you.
你就是凶手
You're the killer.
你去假装诊断系统的时候
You poisoned Lupino's cup
在卢皮诺的杯子里下了毒
when you were "running diagnostics."
你弄坏了吊灯 然后救了我
You sabotaged the chandelier, then saved me from it.
然后
And then...
你杀了伍兹
you killed Woods.
很新颖的理论 但我没有动机
A novel theory, but I have no motive.
我只是你的同事 协助你侦查案件
I am simply your colleague, assisting you with a case.
你甚至不是这个故事的一部分
You're not even a part of this story.
是我带你来这儿的
I brought you here.
是你利用了我 你才能出现
Because you made me bring you here.
你不是我的同事
You're not my colleague.
你是个全息投影
You're a hologram.
自我进入全息甲板的那一刻你就在这了
You have been since the moment I walked into the holodeck.
我让计算机为我量身定制一个谜题
I asked the computer for a mystery made for me,
然后你就是谜题 因为
and it gave me you, because, well,
电脑看到了我之前和真的史波克在一起 并且
it watched me earlier with the real Spock, and...
它知道我从不怀疑他
...it knew I'd never suspect him.
非常精彩 拉安·努尼恩·辛格上尉
Bravo, Lieutenant La'An Noonien-Singh.
你解决了这个谜题
You have solved the mystery.
计算机
Computer...
结束程序吧
...end program?
尽管全息甲板技术确实有潜力
While holodeck technology certainly holds promise,
但是风险实在是多于它的优点
the risks outweigh the potential benefits.
我们不推荐把该装置安装在现役星舰上
We do not recommend the device be installed on active ships...
目前如此
at this time.
我们干脆建议把它用箱子锁起来
How about we recommend that it be locked
埋进暗无天日的地里吧
in a box deep underground somewhere?
呃 如果我可以小小的补充一下
Well, if I could just make one wee, tiny addendum.
它只是需要一个独立的服务器机房
It-it just needs a dedicated server room
然后供能也得是独立的
and power source that--
记在报告里吧 不过只作为脚注
Include it in the report, but as a footnote.
用小字体
In small print.
中尉
Lieutenant?
你知道在船上我们有多少船员吗
Do you know how many crew we have on board?
呃
Uh...
203个人
203.
具体的讲 有整整203名星际舰队最优秀的现役军官
Specifically, 203 of the finest Starfleet has to offer.
当你需要帮助的时候
There is never any reason
永远没有必要独自去抗担子
to do something alone when you need help.
是啊 但如果有呢
Yeah, but what if there is?
在驭星者号遇上戈恩人的前一周
About a week before my last ship ran into the Gorn,
我当时正在建传感器阵列
I was building a sensor array.
我好像发现了一些异常
I thought I saw some anomalies,
但是没有时间去调查它
but I didn't have time to finish it.
我的指挥官说她会去看看 但她没有 然后我们就
My CO said she would, but she didn't, and then we...
驭星者号的事情不是你的错
What happened on the Stardiver wasn't your fault.
我们的工作很艰难
What we do here is hard,
而且时常会发生不幸
and sometimes bad things happen.
但船员们是一个团体
But this crew is a team.
知道何时向别人寻求帮助不是什么弱点
Knowing when to ask for help isn't a weakness.
而是一种力量
It's a strength.
也是舰长和我非常重视的品德
One the captain and I value very highly.
感谢你愿意来完成我们之前的课程
Thank you for agreeing to finish our lesson from earlier.
不用谢
Of course.
计算机 播放歌单 史波克二十一号
Computer, begin playlist: Spock 21.
所以 我想你对全息甲板的谜题测试
So I take it the holodeck mystery test was not
不是很满意
to your satisfaction.
我想要的是单人向的解密
Well, I requested a solo mystery,
但是全息甲板让我误以为我需要一个搭档
yet the holodeck led me to believe I needed a partner.
我找了你
You.
它误解了你的要求吗
It misunderstood your prompt?
这个嘛 我想它理解的非常到位
That, I think it understood perfectly.
我只是没有想到
I just didn't take into account
全息甲板比我想的更了解我
that the holodeck knew me better than I realized.
它给了我一个我从未设想到的嫌疑人
It gave me a suspect I never anticipated.
十分有趣的技术
Interesting technology.
你是怎么破除它的诱导的
How did you deduce this twist?
我一开始真被骗到了
I didn't at first.
完全跟着错误的线索链调查
I was looking for clues in all the wrong places.
但我现在理解了它到底出的是什么题
But now I understand the puzzle it built for me.
愿闻其详
And what was that?
它用全息投影复刻了一个你
It created a holographic version of you
头脑清晰 有逻辑
that was clear-headed, logical.
冷漠
Cold.
这么形容我很正确
Words that have been used to describe me.
但我
But I...
我了解你
I know you.
我知道你跳舞时手臂抱着我的感觉
I know the feel of your arms when we dance.
我知道我们注视彼此的眼神里有什么
I... know the way we look into each other's eyes.
他看我的样子和你不同
He didn't look at me like that.
也许我之前误判了什么
Or perhaps I've misread the situation.
之前跳舞那次
Earlier today...
我想知道是不是我想太多了
I wondered if it was I who had misunderstood.
因为有那么一瞬间 我以为你想
Because for a moment, I thought that you wanted...
那 你也想吗
And... did you also want?
我们要吃掉人类凉皮
We will eat the human food-pies!
是凉皮 还是粮堆来着
Is it... is it pies, or piles?
是堆
It's piles.
皮吗
Pies?
向左
Left.
回来 向右 向右
And back. Right, right, right.
往右啊
And right!
这个怎么样
How's this?
这样呢
How about this?
天杀的
Goddamn it!
小心衣服
Costumes!
各位 这是星云吗
You guys, is it "nebula"?
哇哦
Whoa!
那我们需要帮助
Then we'll need a leg up.
-这是我的台词 -我以为这是我的台词
- That's my line! - I thought I had the leg bit.
-台词 -什么 为什么你要讲这句
- Line? - What? Why would you have the leg bit?
我不知道 我以为我有这句台词
I-I don't know. I thought I had the leg bit.
这很明显是我的台词 是舰长的台词
Well, it's clearly my line! It's a captain's line.
为什么她有这句台词
Why would she have the leg bit?
这是我的台词
It's my line.
是啊 我们正在等信号
Yeah. We're waiting on sound.
红色皮革 黄色皮革
Red leather, yellow leather.
嘿
Hey.
我收不到她的信号了
I've lost her.
我收不到了
I've lost her!
老天啊 我只是想跨过这个椅子
Jesus Christ. I was trying to get my leg over.
这个椅子 就不能
Can... this chair...
有人能修下这个椅子吗 求求了
Can someone fix the chair? Please?
我不能坐这玩意
I'm... I w... I can't work like...
开门
Open the door.
救命 救命
Help. Help!
好了 我扶住你了
Yeah, I got you.